Ms. NISHA DESAI B. Tech. [Instrumentation and Control engineering]

13, Gadhpur Township, Near Navjivan Restaurant, Surat-394326| +919313809424| nishadesai9979@gmail.com

OBJECTIVES:

Instrument Engineer with more than two years' experience who is committed to work, passionate, and accountable. Excellent leadership, management, and planning abilities. possess extensive expertise in coordinating efforts between various departments and planning, implementing, and engineering. Looking for opportunity where I can hone my existing skills, pick up new ones, and help a company succeed as a whole is what I'm looking for

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:

Qualification	Institute/University	Year of Passing	Result
B.Tech (Instrumentation and Control Engg.)	Institute of Technology, Nirma University, Ahmedabad	June, 2020	8.41 (CPI)
HSC/12 th (GSHSEB)	Kaushal Vidyabhavan, Surat.	March, 2016	91.66% (PCM) 86.30% (Overall)
SSC/10 th (GSEB)	Kasturba Vidyabhavan, Surat.	March, 2014	84.00%

PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN:

- 1) Developed and Implemented a logic for standing alarm detection in Foxboro DCS System. (April 2023-Present)
- 2) Online Lube oil monitoring system applied in Main Drive Gear Box for the real time data monitoring in DCS system. (March2023 –Present)
- 3) FCP270 to FCP280 upgradation as per Company OEM Requirements. (August 2022 Present)
- 4) Implemented pump trip logic on high temperature for 96 pumps of product area in DCS system for PO Automation. (August 2021 September 2021)
- 5) First out logic implement in Allen-Bradley PLC and also implement graphics for panel operator in DCS System for the same. (July 2021 August 2021).
- 6) ESD logic testing for ESD hardware upgradation system. (April 2021 May 2021).
- 7) GSM based Water Quality Measurement using Arduino. (Major Project /January 2020 May 2020)
- 8) Prototype Development of Home Automation System. (Minor Project /July 2019-November 2019)

CERTIFICATION:

- Python for Data Science, AI & Development, IBM, Aug 2022
- Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python), University of Michigan, Aug 2022

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE:

Reliance Industries Limited (Feb 2021 – Present)

INSTRUMENTATION AND CONTROL MANAGER. • SEZ-Polypropylene • Jamnagar, Gujarat

• Prepared daily report of Instrumentation jobs such as regular PM and CM of different transmitters, Control valves and Pumps in plant. Apart from this review the P&ID drawings, Electrical wiring diagram and instruments datasheets for the selection of field instruments, MOC and commissioning purpose.

- Handle the annual plant Audits for the Safe operation and reliability of plant and also handle the final inspection of plant during Mega shutdown activity.
- As a reliability point of view handle all the material management in SAP, MMCS and Permit management in SAP as well as RCOW portal.
- Develop, manage and execute proper functioning of systems. Implement system and tools to collect and analyze signal processing data.
- Design, installation and maintenance of a control system and to make sure it runs uninterrupted and troubleshooting of systems.
- Worked on DCS and PLC for data trends and data analysis of different values in transmitters and also logic and graphics implementation in DCS as well as PLC.

Reliance Industries Limited (June 2019 – July 2019)

INTERNSHIP • Jamnagar, Gujarat

- Study on Establishing Test set up for DCS, ESD and PLC and successfully commissioned the integration of control system of tank farm.
 - After Completion of the project to receive a pre-placement offer from Reliance Industries limited to continue working in this field after graduation because of my great performance and close to perfect outcomes.

ACHIEVEMENTS & AWARDS:

- Awarded "R-Samman" for the team work and ownership mindset with remarkable contribution during SEZ PP Mega shutdown (October-2022)
- Awarded "R-Samman" for the completion of project, titled, "Implemented pump trip logic on high temperature for 96 pumps of product area in DCS system with ownership mind set".
- Achieved 5th merit rank in graduation (Instrumentation and Control Engineering, 2020).
- Got pre incubation funding for the major project on "GSM based Water Quality Measurement System" from Centre for Entrepreneurship cell, Nirma University.
- Offered admission under Tuition Fee Waiver Scheme for graduation in Nirma University as a meritorious student.

SKILLS:

SOFTWARES: • SIMATIC S7 (PLC) • RS Logix 5000(AB PLC) • Ms Office

KNOWNTristation(ESD)MULTISIMPython (Open CV)

• SAP • Foxboro Invensys(DCS) • SIMULINK

SUBJECT OF
 Process Automation
 Parameter Measurement
 Industrial Communication
 Power plant Automation
 Elements of Electronics

• Signal Processing • Embedded system and network design

MANAGEMENT • Leadership • Problem solving • Time Management

SKILLS: • Communication • Team Work • Project Management

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Date of Birth: 31/08/1998
Gender: Female
Nationality: Indian

• Languages Known: English, Hindi, Gujarati

• Hobbies: Badminton, Travelling, Listening Music, Reading